Register of the Charls E. Walker Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Charls E. Walker papers,
1946-1997
2001C23
Walker, Charls E. (Charls Edward), 1923-
37 manuscript boxes 15.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, and printed matter, relating to American economic conditions, American economic policy, especially during the presidential administrations of Dwight D. Eisenhower and Richard M. Nixon, and especially to banking and taxation issues.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1923 Dec. 24 Born, Graham, Texas
1947 B.A., University of Texas
1947-1954 M.B.A., University of Texas
1948-1950 Instructor of finance, University of Pennsylvania
1948-1954 Instructor, Assistant Professor, and Associate Professor of finance, University of Texas
1949 Married Harmolyn Hart
1953-1954 Financial economist at the Federal Reserve Bank, Pennsylvania
1954-1961 Financial economist at the Federal Reserve Bank, Dallas
1955 Ph.D. in economics, Wharton School of Finance, University of Pennsylvania
1958-1961 Assistant to the Secretary of the Treasury Robert B. Anderson
1961-1969 Vice president, American Bankers Association
1969-1972 Under Secretary of the Treasury
1973 Deputy Secretary of the Treasury
Scope and Content Note
The Charls E. Walker papers consist of material related to Charls E. Walker's professional life in business and government. They include biographical material, correspondence, memoranda, speeches, writings, and printed matter reflecting his long career in banking, and his tenure as Under Secretary (1969-1973) and Deputy Secretary of the Treasury (1973).
Of particular interest is material related to his career in the Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas, and his close relationship to the business and academic community of Texas, reflected in numerous appearances and speeches before academic and business groups, found in the SPEECHES AND WRITINGS series. The collection also includes extensive material about American banking, including the American Banking Association.
The TREASURY DEARTMENT OFFICE FILE contains material related to his tenure in the Treasury Department, including briefings, memoranda, reports, speeches, and writings. An extensive SUBJECT FILE includes material about business associations, and groups such as the American Economic Association, as well as business and the U.S. economy. The collection also includes writings by other economists and political figures.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
United States--Economic policy.; Finance, Public--United States.; Banks and banking--United States.; Taxation--United States.; United States. Dept. of the Treasury.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-
Occupations
Economists.
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1954-1967. (Box 1-2)
  Appointments, clippings about Charls E. Walker, letters, press releases, and telephone call sheets. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Correspondence, 1955-1997. (Box 3-8)
  Correspondence of Charls E. Walker with business associates and organizations, and government offices and officials, including the White House. Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- Speeches and Writings, 1954-1997. (Box 8-16)
  Articles, lectures, speeches, transcripts of press conferences, television and radio interviews, and thesis for Ph.D. degree. Arranged chronologically by title
- Writings by Others, 1954-1972. (Box 16-21)
  Writings by individuals in business and government related to Charls E. Walker's activities. Mostly related to business and economics. Arranged alphabetically by name of author
- Banking File, 1951-1980. (Box 21-25)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and writings related to banking and especially the Federal Reserve System. Arranged by subject
- Office File of the United States Department of the Treasury, 1961-1972. (Box 25-28)
  Briefings, memoranda, printed matter, public statements, and reports generated by or related to the Treasury Department. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Subject File, 1954-1980. (Box 28-36)
  Catalogs, correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, and reports, mostly related to business, economics, and politics. Arranged alphabetically by subject
- Printed Matter, 1954-1965. (Box 36)
  Articles on economics, catalogs of books about economics, and clippings related to business, economics, and politics. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Photographs, 1982. (Box 37)
  5 prints, including 1 print of Ronald Reagan and 1 print of James Brady
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1954-1967 (Box 1)
  - General (Folder 1: 1)
  - Clippings (Folder 1: 2-6)
  - Letters of appointment and promotion (Folder 1: 7-8)
  - Letters of appointment and promotion (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
  - Letters received upon resignation from the Department of the Treasury. Mostly from members of Congress and the administration, 1973 (Folder 2: 3-4)
  - Letters of recommendation (Folder 2: 5)
  - Press releases (Folder 2: 6)
  - Security clearance (Folder 2: 7)
  - Telephone call sheets (Folder 2: 8-9)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1955-1997. (Box 3)
  Includes memoranda and prepared comments
  - General
    - General, 1969-1972
      - A-H (Folder 3: 1)
      - K (Folder 3: 2)
      - L (Folder 3: 3-4)
      - M (Folder 3: 5-6)
      - Mc (Folder 3: 7)
      - N (Folder 3: 8)
      - O (Folder 3: 9)
      - P (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
      - Q (Folder 4: 3)
      - R (Folder 4: 4-5)
      - S (Folder 4: 6-7)
      - T (Folder 4: 8)
      - U (Box-folder 5: 1)
      - V (Folder 5: 2)
      - W (Folder 5: 3-4)
      - Y-Z (Folder 5: 5)
    - White House.
      Includes memoranda for members of the presidential staff
      - Bush, George (Folder 5: 6)
      - Clinton, Bill (Folder 5: 7)
      - Ford, Gerald (Folder 5: 8)
      - Reagan, Ronald (Folder 5: 9)
  - Allen, Richard, 1981 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Anderson, Martin, 1982 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Archer, John, 1960 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Baird, Julian, 1959-1961 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Baker, James, 1982-1987 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Baker, Robert, 1960 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Baldridge, Malcolm, 1981-1985 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Barden, Charles, 1981 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Barr, Joseph, 1960 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Bartelt, E. F., 1955 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Baughn, W. H., 1959 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Blumenthal, Michael, 1977 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Boggs, Daniel, 1981 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Bolling, Jim, 1976 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Boren, Walter, 1960 (Folder 6: 10)
  - Brock, William, 1984-1985 (Folder 6: 11)
  - Buchanan, Patrick, 1985 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Buehler, Robert, 1960 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Bush, George, 1984 (Folder 6: 14)
  - Bush, Prescott, 1960 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Cannon, James, 1975-1976 (Folder 6: 16)
  - Cavaney, Red, 1982 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Chapoton, John, 1981 (Folder 6: 18)
  - Cheney, Richard, 1975 (Folder 6: 19)
  - Chew, David, 1983 (Folder 6: 20)
  - Christie, Milton, 1960 (Folder 6: 21)
  - Clarke, David, 1960 (Folder 6: 22)
  - Colean, Miles, 1960 (Folder 6: 23)
  - Conte, Silvio, 1960 (Folder 6: 24)
  - Costa, Aubrey, 1960 (Folder 6: 25)
  - Curtis, Lawrence, 1960 (Folder 6: 26)
  - Dam, Kenneth, 1983 (Folder 6: 27)
  - Darman, Richard, 1985 (Folder 6: 28)
  - Davis, Kenneth, 1981 (Folder 6: 29)
  - Dorsey, Harold, 1960 (Folder 6: 30)
  - Duberstein, Kenneth, 1983-1988 (Folder 6: 31)
  - Eisenstat, Stuart, 1977-1980 (Folder 6: 32)
  - Fink, Orman, 1960 (Folder 6: 33)
  - Freidersdorf, Max, 1974 (Folder 6: 34)
  - Gainsbrugh, Martin, 1957-1961 (Folder 6: 35)
  - Gates, Brad, 1982 (Folder 6: 36)
  - Gergen, David, 1981 (Folder 6: 37)
  - Ginsburg, Bob, 1977 (Folder 6: 38)
  - Godley, Gene, 1977 (Folder 6: 39)
  - Griscom, Thomas, 1987 (Folder 6: 40)
  - Guin, Leslie, 1961 (Folder 6: 41)
  - Gunn, Wendell, 1984 (Folder 6: 42)
  - Haig, Alexander, 1982 (Folder 6: 43)
  - Harper, Edwin, 1983 (Folder 6: 44)
  - Heller, Walter, 1959-1960 (Folder 6: 45)
  - Hemmel, Eric, 1983 (Folder 6: 46)
  - Herrington, John, 1983 (Folder 6: 47)
  - Hicks, Christopher, 1982 (Folder 6: 48)
  - High, George, 1988 (Folder 6: 49)
  - Honegger, Barbara, 1982 (Folder 6: 50)
  - Hunter, Clarence, 1960 (Folder 6: 51)
  - James, Pendleton, 1981 (Folder 6: 52)
  - Johnson, Norris, 1956 (Folder 6: 53)
  - Johnson, Richard, 1960 (Folder 6: 54)
  - Kimmitt, Bob, 1960-1985 (Folder 6: 55)
  - Kudlow, Lawrence, 1981 (Folder 6: 56)
  - Laitin, Joseph, 1977 (Folder 6: 57)
  - Lance, Bert, 1977 (Folder 6: 58)
  - Larkin, Fritz, 1960 (Folder 6: 59)
  - Law, Warren, 1960 (Folder 6: 60)
  - Lay, Kenneth, 1992. (Folder 6: 61-62)
    Includes correspondence with George Bush
  - Lee, Arthur, 1960 (Folder 6: 63)
  - Lee, Maurice, 1960 (Folder 6: 64)
  - Lewis, Drew, 1981 (Folder 6: 65)
  - Livingston, Joseph, 1960 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Marsh, John, 1976 (Folder 7: 2)
  - Martin, Tom, 1960 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Matthews, Elbert, 1960 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Mayo, Robert, 1960 (Folder 7: 5)
  - McBride, Pierre, 1960 (Folder 7: 6)
  - McFarlane, Robert, 1983 (Folder 7: 7)
  - McMahon, Christopher, 1960 (Folder 7: 8)
  - McNamar, R. T., 1981-1982 (Folder 7: 9)
  - McSween, Harold, 1960 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Meese, Edwin, III, 1981-1983 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Miller, William, 1979 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Murchison, Kenneth, 1960 (Folder 7: 13)
  - Nelson, Frederick, 1960 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Nevius, John, 1982 (Folder 7: 15)
  - Noyes, Guy, 1960 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Paddleford, Valerie, 1960 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Pendleton, James, 1981 (Folder 7: 18)
  - Penick, William, 1983 (Folder 7: 19)
  - Pierce, Samuel, 1981 (Folder 7: 20)
  - Porter, Roger, 1985 (Folder 7: 21)
  - Proxmire, William, 1960 (Folder 7: 22)
  - Quayle, Dan, 1992 (Folder 7: 23)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1980-1983 (Folder 7: 24)
  - Regan, Donald, 1981-1982 (Folder 7: 25)
  - Rogers, John, 1985 (Folder 7: 26)
  - Schlesinger, James, 1977-1979 (Folder 7: 27)
  - Schoeppel, Andrew, 1960 (Folder 7: 28)
  - Schwengel, Fred, 1960 (Folder 7: 29)
  - Segal, Joel, 1960 (Folder 7: 30)
  - Seidman, William, 1975-1988 (Folder 7: 31)
  - Sethness, Charles, 1985 (Folder 7: 32)
  - Shanahan, Eileen, 1970-1977 (Folder 7: 33)
  - Shaw, Edward, 1960 (Folder 7: 34)
  - Shivers, Allan, 1960 (Folder 7: 35)
  - Shriver, Sargent, 1969 (Folder 7: 36)
  - Shultz, George, 1983-1986 (Folder 7: 37)
  - Simon, William, 1969 (Folder 7: 38)
  - Sisler, Joe, 1960 (Folder 7: 39)
  - Slonaker, Thomas, 1983 (Folder 7: 40)
  - Smathers, George, 1960 (Folder 7: 41)
  - Smith, Aubrey, 1960 (Folder 7: 42)
  - Smith, Dan Throop, 1969 (Folder 7: 43)
  - Smith, W. A., 1960 (Folder 7: 44)
  - Sowell, O. James, 1960 (Folder 7: 45)
  - Spears, Charles, 1969 (Folder 7: 46)
  - Stark, Morton, 1972 (Folder 7: 47)
  - Stark, Walter, 1960 (Folder 7: 48)
  - Stinson, George, 1971 (Folder 7: 49)
  - Stockman, David, 1980-1981 (Folder 7: 50)
  - Stout, Anthony, 1981 (Folder 7: 51)
  - Strauss, Robert, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 52)
  - Strunk, Norman, 1969-1971 (Folder 7: 53)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur, 1981 (Folder 7: 54)
  - Symington, Stuart, 1960 (Folder 7: 55)
  - Talmadge, Herman, 1960 (Folder 7: 56)
  - Tarver, Jack, 1971 (Folder 7: 57)
  - Terborgh, George, 1972 (Folder 7: 58)
  - Thomas, Essell, 1960 (Folder 7: 59)
  - Thompson, Bruce, 1985 (Folder 7: 60)
  - Tienken, Robert, 1960 (Folder 7: 61)
  - Ture, Norman, 1981 (Folder 7: 62)
  - Unger, Sherman, 1981 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - VanScoyoc, H. S., 1985 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Veneman, John, 1976 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Volcker, Paul, 1983 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Waggoner, Joe, 1969-1972 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Watson, C. E., 1960 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Weinberger, Caspar, 1981 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Weiss, Arnold, 1982 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Westland, Jack, 1960 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Whitehead, John, 1981 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Whittemore, Charles, 1960 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Wilde, Frazer, 1960 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Willan, Robert, 1982 (Folder 8: 13)
  - Wolfe, Leonard, 1960 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Wright, Joseph, 1982 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Wright, Thomas, 1972 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Yeutter, Clayton, 1985 (Folder 8: 17)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1954-1997.
  Typescript unless otherwise indicated
  - General
    - General (Folder 8: 18)
    - Correspondence and printed matter related to speeches delivered (Folder 8: 19)
    - Letters to the editor (Folder 8: 20)
    - Lists
      - Cancellations (Folder 8: 21)
      - Press conferences, speeches, and writings (Folder 8: 22)
    - Memoranda
      - General (Folder 8: 23)
      - Florence, Fred (Folder 8: 24)
    - Notes (Folder 8: 25)
    - Titles for speeches (Folder 8: 26)
    - Testimony before congressional committees (Folder 8: 27-30)
    - Writings for or with others (Box 9)
      - Florence, Fred
        - 1955 (Folder 9: 1-13)
        - 1956 (Folder 9: 14-31)
        - 1957-1959. (Folder 10: 1)
          Includes newspaper clippings re Fred Florence
      - Irons, Watrous
        - 1954 (Folder 10: 2)
        - 1955 (Folder 10: 3)
        - 1956 (Folder 10: 4)
        - 1957 (Folder 10: 5)
        - 1958 (Folder 10: 6)
        - 1959 (Folder 10: 7)
        - 1961 (Folder 10: 8)
  - Remarks, Dallas Graphic Arts association, Dallas, Texas, n.d. (Folder 10: 9)
  - "Business Activity in the United States," n.d. (Folder 10: 10)
  - "Increasing Public Understanding of Monetary Policy: A Job for Bankers," n.d. (Folder 10: 11)
  - "A Note on the Economic Theory of Socialism," n.d. (Folder 10: 12)
  - Thesis for Ph.D., Wharton School of Finance, University of Pennsylvania, 1955. (Folder 10: 13-17)
    Includes charts, correspondence, and drafts
  - Thesis for Ph.D., Wharton School of Finance, University of Pennsylvania, 1955. (Box-folder 11: 1-4)
  - "Eleventh District Banking Trends in 1954," Monthly Business Review, 1955 May 1. (Folder 11: 5)
    Printed copy
  - "Policies to Combat Depressions," book review, 1956. (Folder 11: 6)
    Includes correspondence
  - "Interpreting Federal Reserve Policy," Mortgage Bankers Association of America, Southern Methodist University, 1956 January 28 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Speech, Southwestern Social Science Association, Oklahoma City University, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, 1956 March 29 (Folder 11: 8)
  - "Business and Banking 1956," Arkansas Bankers Association, Hot Springs, Arkansas, 1956 May 21 (Folder 11: 9)
  - "The Business Outlook," Republic National Bank of Dallas, Dallas, Texas, 1956 June 22 (Folder 11: 10)
  - "The Business Situation and Its Implications for Municipal Finance," Second Government Accounting and Finance Institute, Austin, Texas, 1956 July 2 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Lecture, Executive Development Program, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, 1957 February. (Folder 11: 12)
    Correspondence and programs
  - "Sources of Funds for Working Capital and Fixed Capital Purposes," Institute of Management, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, 1957 February 18 (Folder 11: 13)
  - "Federal Reserve Policy in a Dynamic Economy," the First District Texas Bankers Association, Houston, Texas, 1957 February 9 (Folder 11: 14)
  - Untitled article on small business for Review, 1957 March 6 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Speech, Alamo Kiwanis Club, San Antonio, Texas, 1957 April 4. (Folder 12: 2)
    Correspondence
  - Speech, Rotary Club of Corpus Christi, Corpus Christi, Texas, 1957 September 19. (Folder 12: 3)
  - Speech, Dallas Retail Credit Managers Association, Inc., Dallas, Texas, 1957 October. (Folder 12: 4)
  - "Report of the Subcommittee of the Special Committee on Studies of the Banking Structure of the Conference of Presidents," 1957 October 1 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Speech, Tyler Area Chapter, Texas Manufacturers Association, Tyler, Texas, 1957 October 16. (Folder 12: 6)
  - "Lessons of Monetary Experience Since the Treasury-Federal Reserve Accord," Tulane University, 1957 November 15 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Lecture, Sixth Annual Development Course, Texas A&M, College Station, Texas, 1958 February 7-8. (Folder 12: 8)
  - Presentation, University of Texas, Executive Development Program, Austin, Texas, 1958 March 10-12. (Folder 12: 9)
  - Speech, Austin Conference of NABAC, Taylor, Texas, 1958 March 20. (Folder 12: 10)
  - Speech, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, 1958 March 25. (Folder 12: 11)
  - Speech, United States Savings and Loan League Management Conference, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1958 April 14. (Folder 12: 12)
  - Address, Dallas Society of CPA's, Dallas, Texas, 1958 April 17. (Folder 12: 13)
  - "Monetary Policy in Our Dynamic Economy," Annual Convention of Louisiana Bankers Association, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1958 April 21 (Folder 12: 14)
  - "Business Stability: What It Means to the American Woman," Women's Finance Forum, Longview, Texas, 1958 April 28. (Folder 12: 15)
    Outline and correspondence
  - Speech, San Antonio Chapter, National Association of Accountants, San Antonio, Texas, 1958 May 6. (Folder 12: 16)
  - Speech, NABAC Texas Oklahoma Conference, Dallas, Texas, 1958 May 29. (Folder 12: 17)
  - Lecture, Tulane University, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1958 July 11. (Folder 12: 18)
  - Speech, Greenville Rotary Club, Greenville, Texas, 1958, July 23. (Folder 12: 19)
  - Speech, Downtown Rotary Club, Dallas, Texas, 1958 August 13. (Folder 12: 20)
  - Speech, Wichita Falls Rotary Club, Wichita Falls, Texas, 1958 August 14. (Folder 12: 21)
  - Speech, Texas Association of Tobacco Distributors, Austin, Texas, 1958 September 19. (Folder 12: 22)
  - Speech, Optimist Club of Dallas, Dallas, Texas, 1958 September 22. (Folder 12: 23)
  - Speech, Rice Institute, Houston, Texas, 1958 October 7. (Folder 12: 24)
  - Speech, Seventh Annual Southwest Regional Conference, Institute of Internal Auditors, Shreveport, Louisiana, 1958 October 10 (Folder 12: 25)
  - Address, Veterans Administration, Dallas Regional Office, Dallas, Texas, 1958 October 22 (Folder 12: 26)
  - Address, American Institute of Supply Associations, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1958 October 28. (Folder 12: 27)
  - "Eleventh District Banking Trends in Recession and Recovery," Business Review, 1958 November (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Speech, Tyler Rotary Club, Tyler, Texas, 1958 November 6. (Folder 13: 2)
  - Remarks, Wharton School of Finance, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1958 November 11. (Folder 13: 3)
  - Speech, West Texas Conference of NABAC, Abilene, Texas, 1958 November 15. (Folder 13: 4)
  - Speech, Baylor University, Waco, Texas, 1958 November 20. (Folder 13: 5)
  - Speech, Agricultural Conference, New Mexico Bankers Association, Las Cruces, New Mexico, 1958 November 24. (Folder 13: 6)
  - Speech, Graham Rotary Club, Graham, Texas, 1958 November 28. (Folder 13: 7)
  - Participant, Forum and Seminar Program, American Institute of Banking, Austin, Texas, 1958 December 8. (Folder 13: 8)
  - Speech, East Dallas Rotary Club, Dallas, Texas, 1958 December 30. (Folder 13: 9)
  - Speech, Tucson Rotary Club, Tucson, Arizona, 1958 December 31. (Folder 13: 10)
  - Speech, Town and Gown Club, Austin, Texas, 1959 January 8. (Folder 13: 11)
  - Speech, Retail Credit Managers Association, Fort Worth, Texas, 1959 January 14. (Folder 13: 12)
  - Speech, National Association of Accountants, Houston Chapter, Houston, Texas, 1959 January 20. (Folder 13: 13)
  - "The Recession of 1957-1958: A Post Mortem," Dallas Retail Credit Managers Association, Dallas, Texas, 1959 January 22. (Folder 13: 14)
  - "Monetary and Credit System of the United States," Executive Development Program, University of Texas, 1959 January 28. (Folder 13: 15)
    Outline
  - Speech, Dallas Assembly of Delphian Clubs, Dallas, Texas, 1959 January 29. (Folder 13: 16)
  - Lecture, Executive Development Course, Agricultural and Mechanical College of Texas, College Station, Texas, 1959 February 6-7. (Folder 13: 17)
    Correspondence and printed matter
  - Participant, Executive Development Program, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, 1959 March 12-13. (Folder 13: 18)
  - "Open Market Operations: Policy and Procedures," Finance Seminar, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, 1959 March 16. (Folder 13: 19)
  - Speech, Park Cities Lion's Club, Dallas, Texas, 1959 March 17. (Folder 13: 20)
  - Speech, Downtown Lion's Club, Dallas Texas, 1959, March 27. (Folder 13: 21)
  - Participant, Twelfth Annual Businessmen's Day, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, 1959 April 7. (Folder 13: 22)
  - Speech, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, 1959 May 5. (Folder 13: 23)
  - "Treasury Debt Management," Western Assembly on Monetary Policy, Lake Arrowhead, California, 1959 May 28 (Folder 13: 24)
  - "Interest Rates in a Free Market Economy," 1959 June 10 (Folder 13: 25)
  - Untitled article for Banking, 1959 August 31 (Folder 13: 26)
  - "Problems of Treasury Debt Management," Annual Convention of the U.S. Savings and Loan League, Dallas, Texas, 1959 November 11 (Folder 13: 27)
  - "Treasury Debt Management," Investment Banking Seminar, Wharton School of Finance and Commerce, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1960 April 15 (Folder 13: 28)
  - "Should the Interest Rate Ceiling Be Removed?" Tax Review, 1960 May. (Folder 13: 29)
    Offprint
  - Speech, Dallas Association of Insurance Agents, 1961 February 6. (Folder 13: 30)
  - "Economic and Financial Developments," the Houston Personnel Association, Houston, Texas, 1961 February 8. (Folder 13: 31)
  - "I Could Balance That Budget," Graham Rotary Club, Graham, Texas, 1961 February 10. (Folder 13: 32)
  - "Debt Management," Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, 1961 February 16. (Folder 13: 33)
  - Speech, Tucson Rotary Club, Tucson, Arizona, 1961 February 22. (Folder 13: 34)
  - Participant, Southwestern Executive Development Program, University of Houston, Houston, Texas, 1961 March 22 (Folder 13: 35)
  - Press briefing, Department of the Treasury, Washington, D.C., 1969 February 7 (Folder 13: 36)
  - Press briefing, Department of the Treasury, Washington, D.C., 1969 February 10 (Folder 13: 37)
  - Press conference, the Columbus Club, Columbus, Ohio, 1969 March 6 (Folder 13: 38)
  - Remarks before the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, Washington, D.C., 1969 March 21 (Folder 13: 39)
  - Press briefing, Department of the Treasury, 1969 March 24 (Folder 13: 40)
  - Press briefing, Department of the Treasury, 1969 April 21 (Folder 13: 41)
  - Interview, CBS Morning News, 1969 April 22 (Folder 13: 42)
  - Remarks, Texas Bankers Association, 1969 May 5 (Folder 13: 43)
  - Remarks, Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island, 1969 May 23 (Folder 13: 44)
  - Press conference and remarks, Union League Club, New York, N.Y., 1969 May 29 (Folder 13: 45)
  - News conference, Rockford, Illinois 1969 June 3 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Interview, "The Evans-Novak Report," WTTG-TV, Washington, D.C., 1969 July 16 (Folder 14: 2)
  - Press conference, San Francisco, 1969 July 18 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Press conference, U.S. Department of the Treasury, 1969 July 24 (Folder 14: 4)